

reative Web Developer and Designer with unique background that includes education in fine arts, graphic design and programming. Proven success working effectively both on internal projects with teams as well as in customer facing roles with a variety of clients.

Adventurous and highly innovative – from living on a ship for three months to relocating to another country for a year and even jumping out of an airplane. Values different cultures and different perspectives, an eye for art and design, open-minded, life-long learner and always ready to jump in to new situations and experiences.

Technical Experience

Programming:

JavaScript

Libraries/Framework: jQuery, Meteor, React, D3

Web Mapping: Leafletjs, OpenLayers3 Web Design: HTML, CSS

Software:

Adobe Creative Suite, Sketchup, Microsoft Office, Sublime Text, Webstorm, Source Tree

OS: PC, Mac

Specialized skills:

- Planning, organizing, managing and executing projects to completion
- Version control with Github
- Designing layouts and advertising materials using Adobe Creative Suite
- •Comfortable with taking on and learning unfamiliar tasks

Education

Web Developer Certificate, WebLab Front Range Community College, 2014

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Graphic Design Minor in Business Administration Colorado State University, 2008

International Marketing,

Semester at Sea, Southeast Asia, China, Japan, and Korea, 2006

Visual Arts and Communications Franklin College, Switzerland, 2004 – 2005

Portfolio of Work

Website esm1503.github.io | Github esm1503 | Design creativelittlefish.com

Professional Experience

Web Developer Intern, Digital Globe, December 2014 - February 2015

Worked with the Tomnod.com team, participating in the development team sprints.

- Aided in building an experimental, real-time, interactive mapping tool using Meteor and Leaflet Draw and preparing it for beta testing
- Tested open-source mapping libraries for the efficient presentation of huge geospatial data sets on the client-side resulting in a blog post, blog.tomnod.com/map-visualization-tests, and a prototype using Leaflet, D3 and React

Web Designer, Xylem Design, 2007 - May, 2014

Organizing and implementing web projects, including planning, design, development, content management, initiatives and functionality.

- Oversaw content migration for 4 company websites ensuring accuracy, updated information, continuity, and improved performance.
- Redesigned Xylem's main website to improve UI/UX and offer customized product options for customers

Manage project processes between team members.

Plan and prepare mock-ups, get approvals, and manage marketing materials for as e-marketing, social media sites, stickers, product instructions and posters.

• Spearheaded HTML based email marketing campaign improving communication with over 40.000 customers.

Photograph products, compile and prepare content for multiple websites, create mock-ups for new products and 3D models for custom projects.

Work effectively with up to 10 clients per quarter to produce customized graphic options to improve brand presence at trade shows.

Utilize strong administrative and mathematical skills creating sales reports, daily financial monitoring, banking, reconciling and payroll.

• Saved 100's of man hours each year though development of innovative payroll process improvement project.

Assisting customers over the phone, working with vendors, assist in the hiring process, managing last minute projects and deadlines.

Volunteer, Fort Collins Museum of Art, January 2012 - April 2013

Assisting with exhibit installations/deinstallations including unpacking, placing artwork and repacking. Overseeing condition reports on both incoming and outgoing works.

Designing information handouts for exhibits.

Graphic Design Freelance, 2008 - 2012

Concept design, brand identity design, advertisements, posters, websites, illustration.

Intern, Multiplicity Creative & Fort Collins Now, Art Department, 2007

Designed ads, company logo, posters, and book layouts.